Kurt Liang







Profile

After a decade of teaching and mentoring students in the education industry using traditional teaching methods, I sought to expand my pedagogical skills further. I have ventured into exploring digital tools and innovative techniques that make learning meaningful, artistic, and accessible for students, and never turned back. I love to learn, and I appreciate knowledge and the value of collaborating as well as sharing it with others. My passion for teaching has led me to become a lifelong learner, and constantly seek new ways to improve the educational experience for my students.

Experience

Trainee, Dev Academy – 01.2023-05.2023

- The 17-week intensive bootcamp provided me with valuable experience and equipped me with the skills and mindset needed to succeed as a developer.
- The fast-paced nature of the program challenged me to learn new technologies every day and develop a **developer's mindset** that is essential in a constantly evolving industry.
- Working in pairs and groups with other developers was one of the most valuable aspects of the bootcamp, which taught me how to collaborate effectively and handle conflicts using non-violent communication.
- In my final project, our team built a mini Meetup React App using the knowledge
 we learned during the bootcamp. We also developed our self-learning skills
 learning new technology like Zustand, Google Api, Sendgrip by understanding
 how to read technical documentation and utilise the learning resources available.

Preschool Teacher, team coordinator, Kidz world, Rotorua – 03.2020-08.2022

- Improved self-awareness and communication skills through working with young children
- Developed emotional intelligence and adaptability in a high responsibility role
- Taken on the role of team coordinator since Oct 2021, enhancing leadership and team management skills
- Learned the importance of earning the trust of parents and caregivers in a high responsibility role. Communicate effectively with parents and teachers, addressing their concerns and building strong relationships based on trust and respect.

Gap year, new Zealand – 09.2016-12.2017

- Worked in various industries and collaborated with people from diverse cultural backgrounds
- Learned the importance of understanding and appreciating differences among people
- Developed strong communication and problem-solving skills through traveling around and meet different people.

Language tutor, China - 10.2013-06.2016

- Assisted individuals from a wide range of ages, from 7 to 60 years old, in learning the English language
- Developed organisation and planning skills, assessing the needs of each individual student and tailoring teaching approach accordingly
- Gained appreciation for the value of education and impact on people's lives
- Honed interpersonal skills, learning how to communicate effectively with people from diverse backgrounds and build strong relationships with students.

Education

New Zealand Tertiary College – Graduate Diploma in Teaching, 07.2018-11.2019

ICL Business School – Language Certificate, 04.2018-07.2018

Wuhan Institute of Technology – Bachelor Degree in Chemical Engineering, 09.2010-06.2014

Interests

I am an active individual who enjoys Crossfit and snowboarding to stay fit and challenge myself. In my free time, I enjoy the piano and I am currently teaching myself how to play guitar. I am passionate about self-improvement and lifelong learning, and believe in constantly pushing myself to improve in all areas of my life.

References

Available on Request

021 0846 9847 <u>liangke1991@yahoo.com</u> <u>Linkedin</u> <u>Github</u>